Guide to the Louis Agassiz Fuertes papers, 1892-1954
Fuertes, Louis Agassiz papers,
- Series II. Personal Papers, Loose Sketches, and Manuscript Materials
  - Student Notebooks and Early Sketches
    - School Notebook - 5th grade, c. 1884 (Box 131)
    - Bird Lists, 1898-1902 (Box 131)
    - Ink Drawing - Birds of Prey (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Vertebrate Zoology Drawings (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Pencil Sketch of a Raccoon (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Proof of pen and ink drawing of flying game birds (Box 131, Folder 3)
    - Proof of pen and ink logo of Thomkins County Fish and Game Club (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - Journals and Field Notebooks
    - Sketch book: European Trip, 1895 (Box 21)
    - Log of Florida Trip, begun March 15th 1898; Alaska Expedition, May 28-Aug 12, 1899 (digital copy available); Adirondack Mountains - February 18 - 25, 1901; South and Southwest Texas - April 13 to September 1901, 1898-1901 (Box 21)
    - Photocopy of Log of Florida Trip; Alaska Expedition; Adirondack Mountains and S. and S.W. Texas (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Trip to California, 1903 (Box 21)
      Includes a bird list and a list of paintings sold and information concerning ownership of originals in back.
    - The Standard Daily Reminder(few entries), 1905 (Box 21)
    - The Standard Diary (pocket diary), 1911 (Box 21)
    - Date Book for 1913: Journal of Colombian Expedition, January 8-May 8, 1913 (Box 21)
    - Date Book for 1920 (few entries) (Box 21)
    - Record: Abyssinia, 1926-1927 (unlabelled), October 1926 - February 1927 (Box 21)
      October 4, 1926-February 27, 1927
    - Journal: Abyssinia, 1926-1927, Volume II, March 2-April 30th, 1927 (Box 21)
    - Catalogue: Abyssinia, 1926-7 (Box 21)
      Blank except for numbers and sketch on inside of back cover.
    - Chronological Field Catalogue I: Birds in the Collection of Louis Agassiz Fuertes (also available on microfilm), 1898-1910 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Chronological Field Catalogue II: Birds in the Collection of Louis Agassiz Fuertes (also available on microfilm), 1910-1921 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Bound version of digitized Alaska expedition journal (Box 114)
  - Student Papers and Manuscripts
    - DeQuincy's Boyhood, December 11, 1893 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Macaulay's Horatius, March 14, 1894 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Oxford in Johnson's Time, October 24, 1895 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - The Tuesday Afternoon Coaching Club, November 21, 1895 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - The Advantages of Travel, April 30, 1896 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - The Coloration of Birds, B.A. Thesis, May 2, 1896 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
    - Oliver Wendell Holmes (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Incidents in the Life of John James Audubon (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous essays (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Lecture to the blind (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Notes on bird songs (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Cornell University lectures (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - L.A.F. and his connection with Cornell University (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - National Character As Influenced By Climate (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Relation of Structural Developments and Habits of Birds (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - The Louis Fuertes Story [by Romeyn Berry] (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Manuscript pages of reminiscences written by Mary Katherine Fuertes (Box 22, Folder 18-21)
    - L.A.F.'s childhood (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Narrative of Abyssinian Expedition (Box 22, Folder 23-37)
    - Discussion of owls (Box 23, Folder 1-3)
    - Discussion of dogs (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
    - Game calendar materials (Box 23, Folder 6)
      Handwritten information about the bird for each month. The finished calendar is in Box 120.
    - Manuscript notes about bird portraiture and travels, c. 1911 (Box 31, Folder 13)
      Includes writings on the Farallon Islands, Monterey, Big Bend, Abyssinia, Flamingos and Bird Portraiture
    - Miscellaneous articles by Fuertes (Box 23, Folder 7-9)
      Includes handwritten manuscripts for articles on Falconry, American Birds of Prey, and other birds; Humorous poems. Some correspondence
  - Various Personal Papers and Loose Sketches
    - Menus and Christmas cards designed by Fuertes and a travel brochure (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous printed articles (Box 23, Folder 11-12)
    - Genealogy (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Sketch of swimming holes in Ithaca Creek, c. 1910 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - List of birds (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence not written to/from Fuertes regarding conservation and copies of Senate Bill S. 1452, c. 1919-1921 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Photographs and correspondence mainly regarding the First World War, 1915-1917 (Box 23, Folder 17)
      Contents of both folders contain items from William Lowndes.
    - Booklet with pictures of trees (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous certificates (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - List of books owned by L.A.F. (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Cornell Alumni News, 1902 and 1946 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Book plates and Yearbook of the American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers (1956) (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous clippings (Box 23, Folder 23-26)
    - List of Artwork by Fuertes (Box 23, Folder 27)
      Typed inventory that includes subject, size, medium and if/date of publication, See box 30 for similar list.
    - Copy of Fuertes materials from the Peter Paul Kellogg Collection, #21-18-893 (Box 23, Folder 28)
      Reports of the Cornell University sound recordings based on articles written by Fuertes for Bird Lore in 1913 and 1914. Note reads that there are reprints of the articles but they
    - 10 printing blocks (Box 29)
    - Printing block with image of Fuertes holding a bird, MU-1262 (Box 29)
    - Loose sketches (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Pencil drawing, painting, and original painting for Christmas Card. (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Christmas cards designed by L.A.F. (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sketches of ducks (Box 29, Folder 6)
      Book illustrations. Note reads that it was from a letter dated September 4, 1912
    - Sketch of Plaisance (Box 29, Folder 7)
      Island off the coast of Newfoundland, Canada
    - 3 Small sketchbooks (Box 29, Folder 8-10)
      See also Box 126 for more sketchbooks
    - Inventory of Artwork by Fuertes at the Laboratory of Ornithology (Box 30, Folder 1-6)
      Includes index numbers and locations. See box 23 for similar list.
    - Miscellaneous (Box 30, Folder 7)
      Includes clippings, awards, and speeches
    - Birds of New York book materials (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Biographical Materials (Box 30, Folder 9)
      Includes time line of life events, Cornell University Transcript and a card for a show of Fuertes work at the Cornell Club in 1911.
    - Bank ledger and silhouettes of the Arthur Allen Family used on their Christmas card (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, copies of correspondence and an old container list of correspondence for the collection, 1912-1922 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, copies of correspondence, clippings and a telegram, 1911-1920 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Watercolor geese cut-outs (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Penciled geese cut-outs (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Louis Fuertes Bookplate (Box 30, Folder 15)
      Book plates for H. Volmer, H. Dawn and Wells College were mounted and moved to Mapcase Folder 4
    - Postcard collection (Box 30, Folder 16-22)
      Unsent postcards from travels and a few with Fuertes artwork
    - Booklet of Latin names (birds) (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Annotated book plate (Box 31)
    - Card file of research notes (Box 32)
      Research by Mary Boynton on her father. Includes some correspondence and lists of paintings by Fuertes and their locations
    - Print: "Our Friends the Chickadees," inscribed, signed (Box 116)
    - Letter from George Young, Jr. (Dean, College of Architecture) to George M. Sutton, relating to a dachshund foot scraper and accompanied by a sketch by Fuertes (Box 116)
    - Small pocket knife, inscribed LAF (Box 116)
    - Original Black and White Print "Passage de Quindiu, dans la Cordillere des Andes" (Map-case Folder 1)
    - Sketch by A. H. Thayer, handwritten note, Newspaper clipping, reproduction of a print and "Help Save the Wood Duck" poster put out by the Massachusetts Department of Conservation Division of Fisheries and Game with art by Fuertes, Poster for "Growth of an Artist: Louis Agassiz Fuertes" at Cornell University (Map-case Folder 3)
    - Matted bookplates; matted artist's triangle with small painting; matted sketches of fish from Fuertes' Vertebrate zoology notebook, plates 16 and 18; and matted November/December 1925 issue of The Lincoln magazine with bird illustrations by Fuertes (car colors are matched with corresponding species of bird) (Map-case Folder 4)
- Series III. Printed material (bound)
  - The Amateur Sportsman, September 1910 (Box 24)
  - American Forests, February 1931 (Box 24)
  - The American Museum Journal, May 1915 (Box 24)
  - Arbor and Wild Life Days, The University of the State of New York Bulletin to the schools, February, 1951 (Box 24)
  - Les Artistes d'Aujourd'hui, August 15, 1925 (Box 24)
  - Bird Lore, May-June 1938 (Box 24)
  - Blue Feathers, April 1923 (Box 24)
  - Bulletin, Boston Society of Natural History, October 1927 (Box 24)
  - Bulletin, Boston Society of Natural History, January 1928 (Box 24)
  - Carnegie Magazine, June 1956 (Box 24)
  - The Cornell Era, April 1912 (Box 24)
  - The Cornell Plantations, Spring 1956 (Box 24)
  - The Cornell Widow, June 1942 (Box 24)
  - The Eclipse of January 24, 1925 at the Fuertes Observatory, April 1925 (Box 24)
  - First American Bird Art Exhibition, April 1926 (Box 24)
  - Goodspeed's Catalogue 559 (Box 24)
  - In Memoriam: Louis Agassiz Fuertes 1874-1927, 1928 (Box 24)
  - Journal of Forestry, November 1927 (Box 24)
  - The King Bird, July 1957 (Box 24)
  - The Larger North American Mammals, November 1916 (Box 24)
  - Louis Aqassiz Fuertes, 1874-1927 (Box 24)
  - Nature Magazine, September 1928 (Box 24)
  - Nature Songs and Stories, 1914 (Box 24)
  - The National Geographic Magazine, December 1920 (Box 24)
  - Natural History (pp. 204-213), March 1937 (Box 24)
  - The New York State Conservationist, February-March 1954 (Box 24)
  - The North American Review, October 1921 (Box 24)
  - The Post-Glacial History of Zonotrichia Capensis, December 10, 1940 (Box 24)
  - Revue du Vraie et du Beau, August 25, 1925 (Box 24)
  - The Smaller North American Mammals, May 1918 (Box 24)
  - Some Common Game, Aquatic, and Rapacious Birds in Relation to Man, June 1921 (Box 24)
  - The weekly Preview, April 13, 1921 (Box 24)
  - "The Smaller North American Mammals" from National Geographic Magazine, May 1918 (Box 116)
- Series IV. Prints and Proofs of Illustrations for Published Works
  - Various Prints and Publications
    - Church and Dwight Co. (Arm and Hammer) bird cards (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Draft prints of illustrations for published works (Box 31, Folder 3-10)
      Most have annotations.
    - Color plate (Box 31, Folder 11)
      Copy of plates from Lincoln Magazine (see Map case Folder 4) used as an advertisement for Wayne Color Plate Company.
    - Additional Church and Dwight Co. (Arm and Hammer) bird cards: Series 4 (Box 116)
    - Small published versions of artwork (Box 116)
    - Signed "enhanced" reproduction of Willow Ptarmigan (Box 116)
    - Ornithology: Print entitled "Willow Ptarmigan" (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate for 1909 Calendar
    - Ornithology: Louis Agassiz Fuertes: A Calendar of Game Birds for 1909 - 12 color drawings from nature, 1909 (Box 120)
  - Poster "Birds: Nature's Protectors made by the Arm and Hammer Baking Soda Company (Map-case Folder 2)
  - Matted reproduction of a painting of a Dovekie with notations by Fuertes. Reproduction print of Chestnut-Sided Warbler. (Map-case Folder 5)
  - Great Horned Owl print by Beck Engraving Philadelphia numbered 38 of 1500. (Map-case Folder 22)
  - RMC: Posters for "A Celebration of Birds" (Map-case Folder 24)
  - Birds of Massachusetts and other New England States
    - Ornithology: Bald Eagle; Turkey Vulture; Red-tailed Hawk; Duck Hawk; Osprey; Cooper's Hawk; Marsh Hawk, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 37, Comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Red-shouldered Hawk; Red-tailed Hawk; Broad-winged Hawk, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 40, Comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Great Gray Owl; Barred Owl; Great Horned Owl; Snowy Owl, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 46, Comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Golden Eagle; Bald Eagle; Rough-legged Hawk, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 41, Comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Bob-white; Canada Spruce Partridge; European Partridge, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 34, Comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Passenger Pigeon; Mourning Dove, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 36. Comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Duck Hawk; Pigeon Hawk; Sparrow Hawk, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 44. Comment "A very nice plate"
    - Ornithology: Red-bellied Woodpecker; Red-headed Woodpecker; Northern Flicker, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 52. Comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Screech Owl; Hawk Owl; Richardson's Owl; Saw-whet Owl, undated (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 47
    - Ornithology: Duck Hawk, 1922 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 43
    - Ornithology: Orchard Oriole; Baltimore Oriole; Meadowlark, 1922 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Plate 61
  - Louis Agassiz Fuertes and the Singular Beauty of Birds
    - Ornithology: Swallow-Kite and Stone Curlew (on one sheet), 1927 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Color Plates 22 and 23
    - Ornithology: Texas Jack Rabbit; Louisiana Heron; Poorwill; Wild Turkey; Black-necked Stilt, 1901-1903 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Color Plates 45-49
    - Ornithology: Gyrfalcon and Canvasbacks, c. 1910 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Color Plates 58 and 59
    - Ornithology: Great Horned Owl, 1925 (Box 120, Folder 1)
      Color Plate 60 (label is on back of 59)
  - Birds of New York by Howard Eaton
    - Ornithology: Grebe: Holboell's, Horned, and Pied-billed (see also 150-0020), undated (Box 124, Folder 6)
      Plate 1. 4 copies with comments in pencil and a set of plates in 5 colors
    - Ornithology: American Egret; Sandhill Crane; Black-crowned Heron; Great Blue Heron (see also 201-0060), undated (Box 124, Folder 7)
      Plate 24
    - Ornithology: Double-crested Cormorant; Common Cormorant; Gannet (see also 119-0030), undated (Box 124, Folder 8)
      Plate 9. 4 copies, one with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Buffle-head; Ruddy Duck; American Merganser; Red-breasted Merganser (see also 137-0040), undated (Box 124, Folder 9)
      Plate 10
    - Ornithology: Wilson's Phalaropes (see also 222-0020), undated (Box 124, Folder 10)
      Plate 30
    - Ornithology: Turnstone; Red-beaked Sandpiper; Stilt Sandpiper; Dowitcher; Saunderlings; Knot (see also 222-0020), undated (Box 124, Folder 11)
      Different Versions of Plate 33. 6 Copies, 3 with comments in pencil
    - Ornithology: Killdeer Plover, American Goldern Plover; Black-bellied Plover; Semipalmated Plover (see also 272-0010), undated (Box 124, Folder 12)
      Plate 39. 2 copies, one with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Artic Tern; Common Tern; Sotty Tern; Foster's Tern; Least Lern; Roseate Tern; Black Skimmer, undated (Box 124, Folder 13)
      Plate 7. 6 copies, one labelled and one with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Razor-billed Auk; Black Guillemot; Brunnich Murre; Puffin; Dovekie (see also 036-0031), undated (Box 124, Folder 14)
      Plate 3.
    - Ornithology: Oldsquaw; American Scoter; Surf Scoter; White-winged Scoter (see also 162-0050), undated (Box 124, Folder 15)
      Plate 20. 2 copies, one with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Loon: Black-throated, Common, and Red-throated (see Johnson Museum 58.15), undated (Box 124, Folder 16)
      Plate 2. 2 copies with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: King Eider; American Eider and Harlequin Ducks (see also 162-0050), undated (Box 124, Folder 17)
      Plate 19. 2 copies one with label.
    - Ornithology: Willet; Bartramian Sandpiper (or Upland Plover); Buff-breasted Sandpiper, undated (Box 124, Folder 18)
      Plate 38. 5 copies, two with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Wilson's Snipe, undated (Box 124, Folder 19)
      Plate 32. 4 copies, one with comments in pencil and a set of plates in 5 colors
    - Ornithology: Green Heron; American Bittern; Least Bittern (see also 201-0060), undated (Box 124, Folder 20)
      Plate 23. 3 copies.
    - Ornithology: Redhead and Canvasback (see also 147-0030), undated (Box 124, Folder 21)
      Plate 16. 6 copies, one with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Northern Phalarope (see also 223-0010), undated (Box 124, Folder 22)
      Plate 29. 3 copies.
    - Ornithology: Virginia Rail; King Rail; Clapper Rail (see also 208-0010), undated (Box 124, Folder 23)
      Plate 25. 5 copies.
    - Ornithology: Whistling Swan; Canada Goose; Brant; Black Brant (see also 173-0021), undated (Box 124, Folder 24)
      Plate 22. 4 copies, one with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Ring-necked Duck; Lesser Scaup; Scaup (see also 150-0020), undated (Box 124, Folder 25)
      Plate 17. 3 copies, one with comments.
    - Ornithology: Red Phalarope (see 2662-222-0020), undated (Box 124, Folder 26)
      Plate 28. 5 copies.
    - Ornithology: Long-billed Curlew; Hudsonian Curlew; Eskimo Curlew; Marbled Godwit; Hudsonian Godwit, undated (Box 124, Folder 27)
      Plate 37. 4 copies.
    - Ornithology: Pomarine Jaeger; Long-tailed Jaeger; Parasitic Jaeger; Skua (see also 036-0031), undated (Box 124, Folder 28)
      Plate 4. 6 copies.
    - Ornithology: Caspian Tern; Royal Tern; Black Tern, undated (Box 124, Folder 29)
      Plate 8. 6 copies.
    - Ornithology: Sabine Gull; Laughing Gull; Kittiwake; Ivory Gull; Bonaparte Gull (see also 062-0021), undated (Box 124, Folder 30)
      Plate 6. Comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Ring-billed Gull; Great Black-backed Gull; Herring Gull; Glaucous Gull (see also 054-0020), undated (Box 124, Folder 31)
      Plate 5. Comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Yellow Rail; Little Black Rail; Carolina Rail or Sora, undated (Box 124, Folder 32)
      Plate 26
    - Ornithology: Solitary Sandpiper; Spotted Sandpiper; Lesser Yellowlegs (see also 272-0010), undated (Box 124, Folder 33)
      Plate 36. Comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: American Woodcock, undated (Box 124, Folder 34)
      Plate 31. Comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Gadwall; Mallard; Black Duck, undated (Box 124, Folder 35)
      Plate 12. 2 copies with comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Blue Goose; Snow Goose; American White-fronted Goose (see 169-0090), undated (Box 124, Folder 36)
      Plate 21. Comments in pencil.
    - Ornithology: Shoveler; Wood Duck; Blue-winged Tail (see 2662-144-0010), undated (Box 124, Folder 37)
      Plate 14. Comments in pencil.
- Photographic Materials (Box 25-29, 31, 36-38, 46-61, 112-113, 115-117, 129-130)
  - Photographs and 35mm slides (Box 25-27, 29, 31, 46-61, 112-113, 115-117, 129-130)
    - Photographs of Fuertes' drawings of birds, 28 x 20.4 cm and smaller; 41 photographs (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
      Birds
      Gelatin silver prints
    - Photographs of Fuertes' drawings of mammals, 22 x 16.5 cm; 27 sheets; Two images per sheet (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
      Offset lithographs
    - Photograph pulled from pamphlet: "The Eclipse of January 24, 1925 at the Fuertes Observatory", 11.2 x 7.2 cm; 1 photograph (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Thayer Family, 18 x 13 cm and smaller; 3 photographs (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Neighborhood, 18 x 13.5 cm and smaller; 9 photographs (Box 25, Folder 8)
      Cyanotypes
    - Columbia Expedition, 18 x 13 cm and smaller; 2 photographs (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Portraits of Louis Agassiz Fuertes, 19 x 14 and smaller; 19 photographs (Box 25, Folder 10)
      Cyanotypes (photographic prints)
      Collodion prints
    - Expedition to Saskatchewan, 13.2 x 18 cm and smaller; 2 photographs (Box 25, Folder 11)
      Saskatchewan
    - Studio, 20.3 x 24.5 cm; 1 photograph (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Charles W. Knight, 22.6 x 30.5 cm; 1 photograph; Mounted on board (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Abyssinia Expedition, 1926-1927; 20.5 x 20.8 cm and smaller; 24 photographs; Two photographs have press captions attached. (Box 25, Folder 14)
      Ethiopia
    - Bahamas, 20.5 x 20.8 cm and smaller; 5 photographs, 1 clipping (Box 25, Folder 15)
      Relate to negatives in Box 28, folders 26 and 28.
      Bahamas
    - Fuertes' House, Barrocolorado Sheldrake L.A.F. and M.S.F. in front of studio in Ithaca and c. 1920's Family, 19.5 x 24.4 and smaller; 9 photographs; Several mounted on card (Box 25, Folder 16)
      Ithaca, New York
      Postcards
    - Estevan Fuertes, 25.2 x 17.7 cm and smaller; 3 photographs (Box 25, Folder 17)
      Platinum prints
      Letterpress works
    - Beach Haven party, 16 x 25 cm and smaller; 6 photographs, 1 letter (Box 25, Folder 18)
      Letters
    - (Ethiopia) Abyssinia, 2 items (Box 25, Folder 19)
      Menus
      Newsletters
    - Photograph of an interior of the Brewster Mansion with paintings by Fuertes, 19.5 x 24.8 cm; 1 photograph (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Travel photographs, 1899-1914; 18 x 12.5 cm and smaller; 624 photographs (Box 26, Folder 1-61)
      Photographs of people, animals, and landscapes taken during travel and expeditions. Some photographs taken by Fuertes, some by others whose names or initials are often marked on the verso. Inscriptions included on some photographs. Duplicates of photographs exist in different folders throughout. Folder 34 contains a small print of a photograph that appears in the souvenir album in Box 129-130. Prints in folders 1-10 relate to negatives in Box 28, folders 23-29. Prints in folders 35-40 relate to negatives in Box 28, folders 11-22.
      California
      New York
      Alaska
      Arctic
      Jamaica
      South America
      Landscapes
      Boats
    - Photographs of miscellaneous landscapes, 1901-1924; 12.8 x 18 cm and smaller; 184 prints (Box 27, Folder 1-11, 27, 31)
      Some folders include photographs of indigenous people as well as landscapes.
      Texas
    - Birds and animals, 1899-1920; 12.8 x 18 cm and smaller; 334 prints (Box 27, Folder 13-26, 28-30, 32-44, 46)
      Whaling
      Hunting
      Elk
      Bears
      Squirrels
      Turtles
    - Photographs of artworks, 9.8 x 6.8 and smaller; 14 photographs (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Miscellaneous personal photographs, 19.5 x 23.8 cm; 163 prints (Box 27, Folder 12, 47-55)
      Photographs of family, portraits, travel, animals, and artwork.
    - Woodpeckers (various species), 23.8 x 18.4 and smaller; 7 photographs (Box 27, Folder 56)
      Woodpeckers
    - Owls, 23.8 x 18.4 and smaller; 10 photographs (Box 27, Folder 57)
      Owls
    - Photographs of models of birds (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - Composite photograph of woodpeckers, 33.3 x 20 cm; 1 photograph (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - Composite photograph of owls, 33.3 x 20 cm; 1 photograph (Box 27, Folder 58)
      - Pelican, 19.4 x 23.5 cm; 1 photograph (Box 27, Folder 58)
        Pelicans
      - Hawk, 15.5 x 11 cm; 1 photograph (Box 27, Folder 58)
        Hawks
    - With Thayers in Florida, 9.8 x 9.8 cm; 20 photographs (Box 27, Folder 59)
      Related to negatives in Box 28, folders 28-33, 39-41, and 45.
      Florida
    - Photographs of Ithaca, 1908-1909; 9.8 x 9.8 cm; 29 photographs (Box 27, Folder 60)
    - Daguerreotype of Mary Perry Fuertes (Mother Of L.A.F.), 1850; 9 x 8.3 cm; 1 photograph; Leather case (Box 27, Folder 66)
      Daguerreotypes
      Sixth plate
    - First ski club of Ithaca, 1890-1938; 1 photograph, 1 letter (Box 27, Folder 67)